

Contact

- ★ Egypt/Cairo
- +201000269056
- dev.badr.gharib@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/b
 adr-gharib/
- nttps://github.com/BadrGharib

Skills

Technical Skills

React Redux React Native Redux-Thunk Redux-Saga HTML Java Script ES6 Type Script CSS,SCSS Styled Components Tailwindcss Axios GraphQl Jest Next Git Docker **AWS** DevOps CI/CD **Jenkins** Netlify/Vercel

Prior Skills

C#,C++,
MVC, Unity3D
WCF, Web API
SQL, Azure
WPF(MVVM)
.Net Core, IOT

BADR GHARIB

TECHNICAL LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER (REACT, REDUX)

Profile

Technical Lead Frontend Developer (React, Redux) with more than 5 years of experience as frontend developer and more than 10 years as software engineer in general, who can Design and develop quality, secure, easy to use and high-performance solutions. Troubleshoot and resolve customer issues. Review and provide detailed feedback on peer design and source code

Education

B. Sc. Computer Science

Faculty of Science, Assiut University | 2006 - Present

Experience

Technical Lead Frontend Developer (React, Redux)

G2K Group(https://g2k.ai/) | 6/2019 - Present

- -Designing and building the frontend Projects main architecture.
- -Support frontend team in the technical issues.
- -Train frontend team to follow the best practice in writing code and apply required design pattern.
- -Manage versioning control Git and apply the staging concept to keep track for production and dev.
- -(React, Redux, JavaScript, ES6, CSS, SCSS, Material UI, Git, Docker, AWS,CI/CD,...)

Senior Consultant Engineer(.NET ,React, Redux)

QCENTRIS(https://www.gcentris.com/) | 1/2019 - 6/2019

Support the team in refactoring old projects and apply the best practice architecture in new projects.

(.NET ,React, Redux,...)

Technical Lead Software Developer

G2K Group(https://g2k.ai/) | 2016 - 2018

Develop and support the team in some web applications, Researching and implementing some prototypes applications in many new technology fields such as using AR (Hololens) in security field to detect criminals using face recognition.

(C#, .Net core, MVC, Web API, Unity 3d,...)

Software Engineer

CAELUM(http://caelum-knowledge.com/) | 2010 - 2015

Working as full stack developer in many desktop application related to identification systems like Border Control ,e-Passport and e-ID, Make integration with many of devices and SDKs.

(C#, WPF, WCF, Entity Framework, LINQ, Windows Service, Web Service, ADO.NET and SQL Server)

Projects

Parsifal Platform

it's very big web-based project that used in many different fields (security, retails,) that can present in many different types of maps and deal with any data it is fed with like (Video and audio. The IoT. Sensors and systems) that give the client high level of situational awareness for everything happened around him (react, redux).

Covid19 Project

it's a web-based project used to detect infected persons using thermal cameras, this project help in return football fans to stadium at corona time (react, redux).

Face Recognition Project for Egyptian Grand Museum

it's a web-based project used to detect persons based on a predefined lists using their faces ((react, redux))

Other Projects

Border control, Video Surveillance, New Mexican passport, New Dominican passport

Certifications

2019 - Present **REACT NANODEGREE**

Udacity

https://confirm.udacity.com/3DJCM72S

2021 - Present AWS CLOUD DEVELOPER NANODEGREE

Udacity

https://confirm.udacity.com/PAVD9M6K

2021 - Present AWS CLOUD ARCHITECT NANODEGREE

Udacity

https://confirm.udacity.com/HNP7QTEL

Languages

Arabic (Native)

English (Very Good)

German (A1)